（上条）
夏休み初日
First day of summer vacation:
The sister lying dead on my apartment balcony said her name is "Index".
俺の部屋で行き倒れていた
そのシスターさんは―
自分の名前を
“インデックス”だといった
Apparently, the Magic Cabal is after her.
彼女は魔術結社とやらに
追われてるらしいのだが
Give me a break already.
勘弁してくれよ… ここは
科学の町 学園都市だっつうの
This is the city of science, the Academy City, man.
～♪
#02 Innocentius
The Witch Hunting People
What is... this...
何だよ これ…
Snap out of it, Index!
しっかりしろ インデックス！
どうしたんだよ？　一体
どこのどいつに やられたんだ？
What happened?
Who the hell did this to you?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
うん？　僕たち魔術師だけど
That'd be us, the magicians.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
う～ん… これは また
随分と派手にやっちゃって
Hmm, overdid it a bit, I think.
（上条）なんで…
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）ここまで戻ってきた理由？
Why...
Why did it come back here?
さあね
忘れ物でもしたんじゃないのかな
Beats me.
Maybe it forgot something here.
It had a hood on yesterday. I wonder where it lost that.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
昨日はフードがあったけれど―
あれって
どこで落としたんだろうね
She searched for the mana remaining inside the hood to get back here?
（上条）
フードに残った魔力を
サーチして ここに来た？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
じゃ 私と一緒に
地獄の底まで ついてきてくれる？
Then, would you accompany me to the depths of hell?
こいつは 赤の他人の俺を
戦いに巻き込まないように―
She endangered herself and came all the way back here...
...just to keep a total outsider, me,
from getting involved in the fight...
わざわざ
危険を冒して 戻ってきた？
バッカ野郎が！
You idiot!
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
ふ～ん？　ふんふんふん…
イヤだな　そんな目で見られても
困るんだけどね
Please.
Looking at me like that won't do you any good.
それを斬ったのは僕じゃないし
神裂(かんざき)だって―
I wasn't the one that slashed it.
I doubt Kanzaki intended to draw blood either.
なにも 血まみれにするつもりは
なかったんじゃないかな
That clergy uniform, the Walking Church, possesses absolute protection,
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
その修道服 “歩く教会”は
絶対防御なんだけど
フゥ… 何の因果で砕けたのか
but for whatever reason, it was rendered ineffective...
（上条）なんでだよ？
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）うん？
Why...
俺は 魔術なんてメルヘン
信じらんねえし
I don't believe in this fairy tale of magic...
てめえら 魔術師みてえな生き物は
理解できねえよ
Neither can I understand beings like you magicians...
（握りしめる音）
けど…
But...
お前たちにだって
正義と悪ってもんがあるんだろう？
Don't you guys know things like justice and evil?
こんな小さな女の子を―
Chasing a little girl like this through the crowds...
寄ってたかって追い回して
血まみれにして
Covering her with blood...
With all this in front of you,
can you still call yourself just?!
これだけのリアルを前に―
まだ自分の正義を
語ることができんのかよ？
言いたいことが済んだなら
どいてほしいな
If you're done talking, could you step aside please?
それ 回収するから
I need to recover that.
回収？
Re... cover?
Yes, recover.
そう　回収だよ 回収
Recover.
Recover the 103,000 grimoires that thing holds, to be exact.
正確には それの持ってる
10万3,000冊の魔道書だけどね
Ah, do be careful.
あっ 注意したまえ
君程度の人間だったら―
If people of your level set their eyes even on one grimoire,
they'll be headed down the severely disabled road.
１冊でも目を通せば
廃人コースは確定だから
（上条）
ふ… ふざけんなよ
S-Screw you.
そんな物(もん)
一体 どこにあるっていうんだ？
Where exactly are those things?
あるさ　それの頭の中に
They're right there.
Inside that thing's brain.
一度見たものを一瞬で覚えて
It can memorize everything the second it sees it.
一字一句を永遠に
記憶し続ける能力を持ってるんだ
It has the ability to retain every single word and sentence forever.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
それの頭はね
That thing's mind's seen and memorized forbidden grimoires sealed off all over the world and is like a magical library.
世界各地に封印され
持ち出すことのできない魔道書を
その目で記憶し 保管している
魔道書図書館ってわけなのさ
The thing, itself, doesn't possess the ability to use magic, and thus, is harmless, yes.
まあ それ自身は―
魔力を練ることができないから
無害なんだけど
その10万3,000冊は
少々 危険なんだ
But those 103,000 grimoires are rather dangerous.
だから 魔術を使える連中に
連れ去られる前に―
Which is why we came here to protect it...
こうして
保護しにやって来たってわけさ
...before people that can use magic kidnap it...
Pro-tect...
保護？
Yes... Yes, indeed...
そうだよ そうさ　保護だよ 保護
Protect, protect, yes.
それに
いくら良識と良心があったって―
Besides, no matter how much good faith and good nature that thing possesses,
it doesn't seem it'll be able to resist torture or drugs.
拷問と薬物には
耐えられないだろうしね
そんな連中に女の子の体を
預けるなんて考えたら―
The thought of a girl like her being in the hands of those kind of people...
心が痛むだろう？
...hurts the heart, right?
てめえ…
You little...
Who do you think you are?!
何さまだ！
ステイル＝マグヌスと
名乗りたいところだけど
Stiyl Magnus...
...is how I'd introduce myself,
but just call me Fortis931 for now.
ここは
“Fortis(フォルティス)931”と言っておこうかな
In Japanese, it's something like "the strong," I guess.
日本語では
“強者”といったところか
まあ 語源は どうだっていい
Like the language matters.
魔法名だよ　聞き慣れないかな？
It's my magic name.
Not used to hearing things like this?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
僕たち魔術師って生き物は―
Apparently, we, magicians, shouldn't say our names when using magic.
魔術を使うときに
名前を名乗ってはいけないそうだ
古い因習だから 理解できないけど
I don't really get it because it's an old tradition,
but what is important is the fact that I gave you my magic name.
重要なのは
魔法名を名乗り上げたことでね
Among our people, this magic name is more like a murderer's nickname.
僕たちの間では むしろ…
殺し名 …かな
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
炎よ
Fire...
This... is magic?
これが… 魔術？
魔術なんて得体(えたい)の知れないもんに
通用するのか？
This unknown power... this is magic?
This right hand has the ability to cancel out any supernatural powers,
この右手は
異能の力なら 一撃で打ち消せる
but I haven't seen any supernatural powers other than esper abilities yet.
だけど 俺は まだ超能力以外の
異能の力なんて知らない
"The gift of pain for the giant!!!"
巨人に苦痛の贈り物を！
ハアッ！
フゥ… やりすぎたかなぁ
Did I overdo it?
Poor thing.
残念だったね
まあ そんな程度じゃ
何回やっても勝てないってことだよ
Oh well, with his level, it'd be the same result no matter how many times this is repeated.
（上条）
誰が？
Who...
誰が 何回やっても勝てねえって？
Who are you saying can't win no matter how many times this is repeated?
ハッ… バカな
No way...
…たく そうだよ
何をビビってやがんだ
Damn it, that's right.
What am I sweating about?
あの修道服をぶち壊したのだって
この右手だったじゃねえか
This right hand was the one that ripped up that clergy clothing, right?
You little...
この！
I see...
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
そうか　やっと分かったよ
I get it...
“歩く教会”が誰に破壊されたのか
The one that destroyed the Walking Church was...
世界を構築する五大元素のひとつ
偉大なる始まりの炎よ
One of the five major elements which make up this world...
...the great fire of genesis...
それは生命を育む恵みの光にして
邪悪を罰する裁きの光なり
...the light of blessing which nurtures life...
...and the light of judgment which punishes evil...
While it brings a gentle fortune,
それは
穏やかな幸福を満たすと同時に
冷たき闇を滅する凍える不幸なり
at the same time, it is the frosty misfortune which annihilates the cold darkness.
Its name is fire.
その名は炎　その役は剣(つるぎ)
Its role, the sword!
Show yourself by devouring
my body and show your might!
顕現せよ！
我が身を食らいて 力となせ！
魔女狩りの王 イノケンティウス
The witch hunting pope, Innocentius.
その意味は “必ず殺す”
Its meaning... "kill thy enemy"...
ジャマだ！
Out of the way!
なんで右手が通用しない？
Why?
My right hand's not working?
この炎
消滅した直後に復活してるんだ！
This flame... regenerates right after it's canceled!
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）ルーン
（上条）ハッ…
Rune.
神秘 秘密を指し示す
24の文字にして―
A 24-letter alphabet that indicates "secret", "mystique".
A magical language used by the Germanic people starting in the 2nd century AD.
ゲルマン民族により
２世紀ごろから使われる魔術言語で
古代英語のルーツとされます
The roots of Old English.
Attacking Innocentius is ineffective.
イノケンティウスを攻撃しても
効果はありません
壁 床 天井
Walls, floors, ceilings.
As long as the runic markings in the area aren't erased, it will rekindle itself endless times.
辺りに刻まれたルーンの刻印を
消さないかぎり…
You're... Index, right?
お前 インデックスだよな？
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）はい
Yes.
I am associated with the zeroth church sector of the English Purist Church, the "Necessarius".
私は イギリス清教内 第零(ゼロ)聖堂区
“必要悪の教会(ネセサリウス)”所属の―
魔道書図書館です
I am its grimoire library.
My official name is Index-Librorum-Prohibitorum,
正式名称は―
“Index-Librorum-Prohibitorum(インデックス・ライブロラム・プロヒビットラム)”
ですが
呼び名は
略称のインデックスで結構です
but addressing me by my shortened name, Index, will do.
I am currently operating under
the automatic secretary, John's pen-
現在 自動書記 ヨハネのペンを…
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
君にはできないよ
You can't do it.
To completely erase all the runes placed in this building.
この建物に刻んだルーンを
完全に消滅させるなんて
君には絶対にムリだ
An impossible task for you, I'm afraid.
Ashes to ashes...
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
灰は灰に
塵(ちり)は塵に
Dust to dust!
吸血殺しの紅十字！
Squeamish Bloody Rood!
ヤッバ！
Sh-
ハァ… 死ぬ… ホントに死ぬ…
..die...
I really... die...
ハァ… ホントに死ぬかと思った
I really... thought I was gonna die...
何だ？　これは
What the hell... is this?
これがルーンの刻印？
These are the runic markings?
ハァハァ… しまった！
Shit!
Damn you!
くそ！
ウワーッ！
どうして追ってこない？
Why isn't it coming after me?
あっ そうか！
I see!
The range of the placed runes is only inside this dorm!
ルーンが貼り付けてあるのは
この寮だけなのか
ハァ…
ウワッ！
ど… どこかに通報…
Anyway, I need to call the police!
こ… 公衆電話
Phone booth...
I'm not running away...
ここから逃げるためじゃない
逃げるためじゃ…
I'm not running...
Then, would you accompany me to the depths of hell?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
私と一緒に
地獄の底まで ついてきてくれる？
Who in the world would accompany a complete stranger he just met... to the depths of hell?
出会ったばっかの赤の他人と
一緒に 地獄に落ちようなんて―
考えられっかよ！
What is this? A tactic against Innocentius' flame?
まさか イノケンティウスの炎を
消すために？
ンッ… そんな つまらない理由で
ずぶぬれにされたのか
You got me all wet for such a pathetic reason?
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
イノケンティウスは
どうしたんだ？
Where's Innocentius?
You really had me.
…たく まいったぜ
You're good, man.
あんた すげえよ
I'd have had no chance of winning if you had used
a knife to engrave the markings or something.
正直 ナイフか何かで
ルーンっての刻まれてたら―
勝ち目ゼロだったよ
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）まさか…
Impossible!
Innocentius is a block of 3000 degree Celsius fire!
イノケンティウスは
3,000度の炎の塊
You can't take it out with this small amount of water!
こんな程度で鎮火するものか！
Dumbass.
バ～カ　炎じゃねえよ
Not the fire.
What did you spam all around my home?
（上条）
てめえは 人ん家(ち)に―
なにベタベタ貼っ付けてやがった？
ハハハハッ… すごいよ
だけど 経験が足りないかな
Amazing!
But, you might just lack that experience part.
コピー用紙ってのは
トイレットペーパーじゃないんだよ
Copy machine paper isn't just toilet paper, you know?
A little water won't ruin it, eh?
たかが水にぬれた程度で 完全に
溶けてしまうほど弱くはないのさ
Kill him.
殺せ
バ… バカな
I-Impossible!
My runes aren't erased yet-
僕のルーンは まだ死んでないのに
（上条）インクは…
The ink.
Even if the paper isn't ruined,
（上条）
コピー用紙は破れなくても
水にぬれりゃ―
the water will cause the ink to wash off, you see?
インクは落ちちまうんじゃねえか？
Innocentius...
イノケンティウス…
イノケンティウス！
Innocentius!
（上条）
さてと…
Now then...
ハッ… 灰は灰に
Ashes to ashes!
Dust to dust!
塵は塵に
吸血殺しの紅十字…
Squeamish Bloody...
ちくしょう　そうだよな
Dammit!
That's right.
If I don't want to accompany her down to hell...
地獄の底まで
ついていきたくなけりゃ―
...I just need to...
地獄の底から…
ヒイッ…
...drag her...
引きずり上げてやるしかねえよな！
...out of hell!!!
Oneesama!
（黒子(くろこ)）お姉様！
（美琴(みこと)）うん？
My, Oneesama!
（黒子）
まあ お姉様！　まあまあ お姉様！
My, my, Oneesama!
補習なんて
似合わないマネしていると思ったら
To think you'd be attending extra lessons, which is unlike you;
夜遊びのための
口実だったんですのね
it was actually an excuse for some night fun, huh?
ねえ 黒子
（黒子）うん？
You know, Kuroko?
どこをどう見たら この私が
夜遊びしてるように見えるわけ？
How in the world do you see me as having some night fun right now?
決まっています
It's very obvious.
To go through this place on your trip back from school to the dorm...
こんな場所を通って
学校から寮に戻るのは―
...is such a big detour no matter how you think about it!
どう考えても 遠回りですもの
ちょ… ちょっと用事があったのよ
I-I had something to do.
それより あんたこそ…
On the other hand, why are you-
あっ…
（黒子）そうですわ お姉様
That's right, Oneesama.
私 風紀委員(ジャッジメント)のお仕事で
ここへ まいりましたの
I came here on Judgment business.
The cause of that fire accident...
あの出火の原因 どうやら
能力者の仕業らしいですわよ
...is esper related, apparently.
ふ～ん…
Now, the dispatch function should have been erased.
（上条）
これで 発信器みてえな機能は
消えちまったはずだけど
Anyway, I need to take her to a hospital now.
ともかく 早く
こいつを病院に連れていかなきゃ
But, I don't think she has an ID card for this place.
だけど こいつ
ここのＩＤ持ってなさそうだしな
If she stays in the hospital,
the  information about her will be leaked right away.
うっかり入院なんかしたら
あっという間に情報が漏れる
But, I can't just leave her here, either.
けど このまま
放っておくわけにもいかねえしな
Touma?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
当麻(とうま)？
What's wrong?
どうかした？　顔色悪いけど
You don't look so well.
（上条）
人の心配してる場合か！
早く そのケガ なんとかしねえと
Quit worrying about others!
We need to do something about your wound soon, or...
大丈夫 …だよ
I'm... okay...
If we can stop the bleeding, then...
とにかく
血を止めることができれば…
Hey... Hey!
（上条）
お… おい！
Aren't there any books with healing magic among the 103,000 grimoires you hold?
お前の持ってる10万3,000冊の中に
傷を治すような魔術はねえのかよ？
There are, but...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）あるけど…
（上条）それって…
And that-
君にはムリ
（上条）えっ？
You can't... use it...
Even if I told you the spell...
たとえ 私が術式を教えて―
...and if you were to completely mimic it, your power...
君が完全に
それをマネしたところで―
君の力が きっとジャマをする
...will interfere in the end...
くそ… またかよ
No, not again...
This right hand is to blame again?!
また この右手が悪いのかよ！
It's not your right hand,
君の右手じゃなくて
超能力っていうのが もうダメなの
but it's that you're an esper.
Magic wasn't meant to be used by people with abilities like yours.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
魔術っていうのは―
君たちみたいに才能のある人間が
使うためのものじゃないんだよ
才能のない人間が
それでも 才能のある人間と―
People with no abilities still wanted to achieve
the same things people with abilities were doing...
同じことがしたいからって
生みだされたのが魔術
That was what gave birth... to magic...
That means all the students that have entered the ability development program can't...
なら 能力開発のカリキュラムを
受けてる この町の学生には…
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
うん　魔術は使えない
Yes, they can't use magic.
ちくしょう…
そんなのってあるかよ
Damn it... this isn't happening...
Why... Why is this...
何なんだよ… なんで こんな…
This is the city of students.
ここは学生の町なんだぞ
なのに 学生には…
Yet the students can't-
あっ 学生には？
Not students...
Hey, you said that magic can be used by people with no abilities, right?
おい 魔術ってのは―
才能のない人間なら
誰でも使えるんだったな？
Don't be telling me you're asleep at this hour already?
この時間で もう眠ってるなんて
いわねえだろうな
よし…
Yes, yes, yes.
（小萌(こもえ)）
はいはいは～い
I've strengthened the door as a countermeasure against newspaper salespersons.
対新聞屋さん用に
ドアだけは頑丈なんです
今 開けますよ
I'll open the door now.
Ah, Kamijyo-chan!
あっ！　上条ちゃん
新聞屋さんのアルバイトでも
始めたんですか？
Did you start working part-time at a newspaper office?
What kind of newspaper salesperson does his job by carrying a sister on his back?
シスター背負って勧誘する新聞屋が
どこにいる？
I'm in various kinds of trouble,
ちょっと いろいろ困ってるんで
入りますね 先生
so I'm just coming in, Sensei.
Yep, coming in.
は～い　ごめんよ
ちょちょ… ちょっと
Wai-wai-wai-wait...
先生 困ります～！
This is troubling for Sensei!
I know it's weird to be saying this now but...
（小萌）
こんな状況で言うの 何ですけど
Do you dislike women that smoke?
タバコを吸う女の人は
嫌いなんです？
ヒイッ！
ど… どうしたんですか？ それ
Wh-What happened... there?
Sensei, to be honest...
先生 実は…
Index!
インデックス？
Warning, Chapter 2, Stanza 6.
警告　第２章 第６節
The loss of vital energy due to
blood loss has surpassed the safety level,
出血による生命力の流出が
一定量を超えたため―
強制的に
ヨハネのペンで目覚めます
forcing reboot in John's pen's mode.
In the present state,
現状を維持すれば―
according to the international standard time shown on the clock tower in London,
ロンドンの時計塔が示す
国際標準時間に換算して―
body will lose the minimum vital power...
およそ15分後に 私の体は―
...necessary to maintain life in fifteen minutes...
必要最低限の生命力を失い
絶命します
...and perish.
I would be very grateful to you...
これから 私の指示に従って 適切な
処置を施していただければ幸いです
...if you could follow my instructions and apply adequate treatment.
Sensei, I'm going to call an ambulance.
先生　俺 救急車 呼んできます
You listen to what she has to say, Sensei.
先生は この子の話を聞いて
お願いを聞いて…
Listen to what she asks.
Anyway, just make sure she doesn't lose consciousness!
とにかく
絶対 意識が飛ばないように
As you can see, this girl is religious.
（上条）
この子 このとおり
宗教やってるんで よろしくです
Take care of her.
Okay, okay.
なあ インデックス
何か俺にやれることってないのか？
Hey, Index.
Is there anything I can do?
No.
ありません
The best option for you to take right now... is to leave...
この場における最良の選択肢は
あなたが―
ここから立ち去ることです
（上条）えっ？
If you remain in this room,
あなたが この部屋にいれば―
recovery magic will be erased merely by your presence.
それだけで
回復魔術は打ち消されてしまいます
Ka-Kamijyo-chan...
か… 上条ちゃん
This sister-chan just said something about magic...
今 このシスターちゃん
魔術が どうしたとか…
（上条）
先生… この子のこと お願いします
Sensei, take care of her.
…て えっ？　上条ちゃん！
Wait, Kamijyo-chan!
電話なら そこに…
The phone's right there...
The best option for you to take right now... is to leave...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
この場における最良の選択肢は―
あなたが
ここから立ち去ることです
If you stay in this room,
あなたが この部屋にいれば―
それだけで
回復魔術は打ち消されてしまいます
recovery magic will be erased merely by your presence.
～♪
Next Episode
Use magic to have an angel descend?
（上条）
魔術を使って 天使を降臨？
Hold it, will doing that really heal Index's wounds?
ちょっと待て　そんなんで
インデックスのケガが治るのかよ？
次回 「必要悪の教会(ネセサリウス)」
Next time, "Necessarius".
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる
When science and magic cross paths,
this epic will begin!